Gary Holman

gth.softdev@gmail.com 317.983.4566

Indianapolis, IN https://github.com/gth-softdev

www.linkedin.com/in/gary-holman-soft-dev/

Objective:

I am a Software Developer with over 20 years of progressive experience in software, programming, design, training and end-user support. I am looking for a full time, remote/work-from-home position that requires a dedicated and experienced individual with exceptional customer service and communication skills.

Education:

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Software Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis, IN, October 2020
 - o 12-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training.
- New Horizons Computer Learning Center, Carmel, IN 2009
 - o Credentials: MCP, MCSA and CompTIA Security+
- Andrews University, Bachelor of Business Administration (MIS), Berrien Springs, Michigan, May 1990

Competencies & Functional Skills:

Problem solving, troubleshooting, creativity, visual communication, teaching, technical writing, customer service, critical observation and thinking, organization, Agile methodology, portfolio development, addressing and resolving business challenges.

Technical Skills:

Languages: C#, ASP.NET, API development, HTTP methods, MVC, pair programming

Testing Tools: Unit Testing

Databases: SQL Server, relational databases

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Office tools: MS Office (Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook), MS Visio

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, APIs, stateless components, session validation, responsive web design

Professional Experience:

Controls Specialist, Specified Lighting, Carmel, IN, Sept. 2017 – July 2020

Work Scope:

- Through manufacturer, online and self-training, remain current on the latest control equipment and material from various manufacturers
- Read construction drawings and documents to become familiar with bidding jobs in order to perform accurate takeoff and project estimates
- Maintain up-to-date information regarding control equipment/devices from various manufacturers in order to match the proper equipment for the particular job
- Communicate with engineers and contractors to fully understand specific needs for the project
- Using Oasis software, maintain the controls department schedule for completing project quotes
- Using Planswift software, import construction drawings and perform takeoffs for upcoming projects
- Request and assemble outside material quotes
- Note and document details for each project for reference by team members

Technical Support Representative (T2), Exacq Technologies, Fishers, IN, December 2011 – July 2017 Work Scope:

- Assisted customers, dealers and installers worldwide with use of exacqVision hardware and software
- Provided support via phone and email
- Assisted in on-boarding new employees with initial internal training
- Wrote technical documentation for improving processes, addressing problems, and improving application development
- Educated customers on proper networking technologies and approaches to mitigate potential problems
- Assisted in pre-sales by suggesting appropriate hardware and software to meet clients' business needs
- Designed and established document standards, templates, process control for the team

Previous Work Experience:

Systems Project Leader, Indy Tech Pro, L.L.C., Indianapolis, IN 2011

- Assisted with server migration
- Responsible for Labtech Managed Services rollout
- Managed Axcient backup solutions for business clients

Axcess PC Consulting, Inc., Indianapolis, IN 2010 - 2011

- Assisted in Business Client maintenance programs
- Assisted with residential break/fix issues
- Assisted with virus/malware removal, data transfers, new PC configurations

Self-Employed/Co-Owner, Internet Business, 2003 – 2008

- Involved in all aspects of small business startup from inception
- Designed, created and maintained website
- Purchased and modified inventory software, maintained inventory, photographed product and retouched digital photos
- Created online advertisement and maintained e-commerce for payment systems

Technical Specialist/Multimedia Programmer, Interactive Learning Systems, Inc., Battle Creek, MI, 1997 – 2003

- Developed numerous help systems, web based training programs and QA
- Proficient in CBT production that includes all phases of design, programming and implementation

Database Administrator, Information Resources, Inc., Chicago, IL, 1994 – 1997

- Provided on-site help desk support at the Kellogg Company Headquarters, Battle Creek, Michigan
- Automated database and wrote program queries
- Analyzed users' needs for specific database programming